#### Contact

ambastha.vatsal@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ vatsalambastha (LinkedIn) www.VatsalAmbastha.com (Personal)

## Top Skills

Game Development Unity3D C#

Languages

Hindi

English

# Vatsal Ambastha

VR, Games & Media | Unity specialist | Open Source New Delhi

# Summary

Engineer, consultant, and entrepreneur in the video game and media industry since 2010.

Over the years I've run my game studio, created adtech & monetization products, and on game developer-facing platforms. Since 2016, I've worked as an independent consultant & developer on software projects for industries ranging from military to arts & humanities to video R&D.

Presently, I lead Unity development at ManageXR.com, an MDM solution that helps organizations operate VR at scale. My main indie project right now is www.retroreel.app, a streaming service for classic films. I also make short, experimental indie games.

My open-source projects feature popular Unity repositories for physics, AI, networking, audio/video, UI, and more.

In constant pursuit of software craftsmanship.

# Experience

Freelance

Independent Software Engineer September 2016 - Present (5 years 6 months)

As a consultant and contract developer, I work with teams using the Unity engine for games and beyond.

My experience includes projects in blockchain, video streaming R&D, tourism, adtech, arts & humanities, edtech, industrial training, virtual fashion, in-game eCommerce, and more.

ManageXR Lead Unity Engineer September 2021 - Present (6 months)

Page 1 of 3

#### Greater Delhi Area

Helping organizations scale VR and AR operations with ManageXR, an MDM (Mobile Device Management) solution.

I lead our Unity efforts, developing the client-side software supporting a wide and growing range of XR platforms and devices.

## Digibeings

Co-Founder

June 2019 - November 2021 (2 years 6 months)

Hyderabad, Telangana

Focus on Al-powered virtual humans. Worked on creating an architecture for intelligent CG avatars powered by Unity that could understand speech, formulate replies based on a knowledge base and express in verbal and non-verbal language. Also worked on cloud render streaming for displaying highly realistic avatars on mobile devices.

## dopplr.digital

Software Engineering Consultant January 2021 - June 2021 (6 months)

Social, digital fashion. Worked on code quality & architecture, technical planning along with systems for avatar, clothing, and UI in Unity.

## Moonfrog Labs

Software Engineering Consultant December 2020 - May 2021 (6 months)

Helped finish Carrom Gold. Explored opportunities to help speed up and streamline the development process through best practices, reusable software, and infrastructure.

#### MindTrust

Contract Software Engineer September 2019 - February 2020 (6 months)

Worked on Scuti store, a Mindtrust client. Scuti is a gCommerce (in-game eCommerce) platform that brings real-world retail inside games.

Developers can integrate the Scuti store in their games where players can find attractive offers on products and get in-game rewards for purchases.

The platform aims to create value for players, game publishers/developers as well as retail brands. I worked on the Unity Developers SDK.

The Zero Games Pvt. Ltd.
Software Engineer
January 2016 - November 2017 (1 year 11 months)
Mumbai

Worked on PLAKC, a dynamic in-game advertising solution that let developers monetize their games and helped brands reach game players using non-intrusive, in-game 3D ads.

Upon joining, I kicked off redevelopment of the PLAKC Unity SDK. On a daily basis, it enabled millions of ad impressions, generating revenue for game publishers and value for brands.

Handled all aspects of the SDK from feature additions and refactoring to build, packaging and distribution. I also worked with studios to integrate our SDK with some of the largest celebrity and sports IP based games in India.

#### Firexit Software

Founder

July 2013 - January 2016 (2 years 7 months)

Udupi, Karnataka, India

Formed and managed a team of developers creating successful games like Speed Street:

Tokyo and XPro Rally. The studios' games reached over 5 million unique users. Handled art and design work outsourced by other studios as well. We also worked on monetization, analytics, and engagement tools for a while before the studio closed in late 2015.

# Education

Manipal Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Computer Science · (July 2012 - June 2016)

Lalaji Memorial Omega International School

Cambridge School, Indirapuram